Will Wright

will@wright.is +44 (0)7922 774469 http://pixel.wright.is

Highly creative Front End UI Developer and Designer, with a background in marketing, advertising and graphic design. With over 14 years of experience, having acquired great knowledge and expertise working alongside award-winning professionals crafting innovative solutions that balance strategy, technology and usability.

Twitter @WilliamWright LinkedIn Will Wright

SKILLS

| WEB DEVELOPMENT | HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, Javascript, Django, jQuery, Meteor, Bootstrap, Git, Responsive Development, e-Commerce |
|-----------------------------|--|
| DIGITAL & GRAPHIC DESIGN | Art & Creative Direction, Responsive Design, Email Marketing, Social Media Marketing, Display & SEM/PPC (Google Adwords), Digital & Film Photography, Studio Lighting, Laboratory film processing, Digital post-processing |
| OTHER SKILLS | UNIX, Microsoft Office, Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, Flash, Acrobat, Sketch, QuarkXpress, Coda, Sublime Text, CodeKit, TypeKit, Transmit, Apple Aperture, Adobe Lightroom |

EXPERIENCE

Flavourly.com

UI Developer & Designer Oct 2014 - undefined NaN

As recently featured on the BBC's Dragons Den where we received 4/5 offers of investment, Flavourly helps consumers discover the best, hard to find, gourmet food and craft beer from the nations best independent suppliers via our subscription sampling service. Each month we to match our customers to the most mouth-watering products and deliver them direct to their desk or door! Our online marketplace then makes it super easy to order more of your new favourite products!

- Redesign and responsive development (HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery & Django) of the company's new mobile-first website and eCommerce BrewStore, all of this with usability and a quality user experience as a main focus.
- Design of all printed media such as brochures, flyers, promotional materials, packaging and more.

Simple Financial

Web Development Contract Jul 2014 - Sep 2014

Simple Financial is a Glasgow based group of 4 companies offering bespoke financial services and guidance to the public.

- 3 month Web Development Contract, being responsible for the redesign and responsive development (HTML, CSS, jQuery) of some of the company's new client-facing websites.
- Built a Will Writing web app in Responsive HTML (Bootstrap), CSS, ¡Query and Angular]S.

Kork Wines

Co-founder Apr 2012 - Jun 2014

Kork Wines was an online retailer of carefully curated wines from small and passionate producers from around the world.

- Developed the company's business plan securing a venture capitalist investment of £150k.
- Participated in several trade shows promoting the company and generating new leads and partnerships.
- Sourced products from winemakers all around the world, negotiating over 60 available labels.
- Acquired over 3000 sign-ups during the first year of operation.
- Designed and built a Magento-based eCommerce website for the company (HTML, PHP, CSS, jQuery).

Nautillus Design & Strategy

Digital Creative Director Feb 2012 - Feb 2014

Nautillus is a full-service advertising and design agency with a focus on delivering innovative and strategic solutions through an extensive cooperative network of professionals with diverse specialities, allocated on a per project basis.

- Responsible for digital design, front-end development, social media strategy and display & SEM/PPC campaigns.
- Designed and developed the website, marketing campaigns and online presence for the highly publicised São Paulo Mayorship SP2040 project by the University of São Paulo.
- Provided extensive training for the SP2040 in-house team on management of the website with over 5k visits/day.

Wrightdesign

Front End Developer & Designer Dec 2009 - Jan 2012

Freelancer in the fields of graphic & digital design and development including websites, print and digital advertising (display and SEM/PPC), branding, brochures, CMS, HTML email newsletters, web analytics reports and more.

- Designed and developed FIA Business School's websites, social media strategy, marketing campaigns and branding, increasing visits in over 300%.
- Attracted high-profile international candidates to all 3 FIA Business School MBA programs, enabling them to successfully recruit for 2 classes per year on each program since 2009.

Extra.com

Digital Creative Director Feb 2008 - Dec 2009

Extra.com is an advertising agency offering an attentive integrated service to local businesses.

- Coordinated a new digital department within the agency, which I helped create, staff and train.
- Developed a politician's marketing strategy and campaign, resulting in him being the third most voted for mayor.

Apple UK

Mac Specialist / Creative Mar 2007 - Dec 2007

European Operation Centre in London of the American multinational corporation headquartered in California, that designs, develops, and sells consumer electronics, computer software and personal computers.

- Participated in the launch of the iPhone to the European market.
- Delivered customer training on Mac OS X, iOS and creative software.

WG Communication

Art Director Dec 2004 - Jan 2007

A medium-sized advertising agency with high-profile clients, in the areas of trading, food and beverages, and publishing.

 Directed photo shoots and films, creating and designing numerous published adverts published in national circulation magazines, newspapers, posters, television, radio and online advertisements.

W/Brasil (now W/McCann)

Art Direction Intern Jun 2003 - Dec 2004

One of the world's most creative advertising agencies, awarded over 30 Golden Awards at Cannes and other events.

 6 Month internship creating several published adverts for clients such as AmBev, BR Foods, Redbull and Reebok.

DF Systems (IBM)

Software Development Intern Aug 2001 - Dec 2002

IBM in-house systems development for distance learning platforms.

 Created web-based animations for distance learning programs for the University of São Paulo.

VOLUNTEERING

CoderDojo

Teacher Jan 2012 - Jan 2013

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

EDUCATION

FIA Business School

Feb 2009 - Dec 2010

International MBA GPA: 4.0

University Of The Arts London -Central Saint Martin's School of **Art and Design**

Jun 2005 - Aug 2005

Postgraduate - Communication Design GPA:

4.0

Mackenzie University

lun 2003 - Dec 2006

Bachelor of Arts in Advertising and Marketing Undergraduate studies in Electronic

- Communication and Arts GPA: 4.0

Mackenzie University

lan 2000 - Dec 2003

Engineering - Engineering

Miguel de Cervantes (Spanish)

Jul 1994 - Dec 1999 Secondary School

St. Paul's School (British)

Jan 1985 - May 1994 Primary School

AWARDS

PUBLICATIONS

Portraits of India: the scenes, the people, the beauty

Blurb

2012-07-12

Link

Traveling the world, Will began to observe the relationships people keep between them and the rest of the world. He believes we are all global citizens and it is through photography that he tries to document how people so distant can be so similar to you and me. This book focuses on some of his portraits taken in the streets of India.

LANGUAGES

English

Native speaker

Portuguese

Fluent (Second Language)

Spanish

Fluent (Bachiller Diploma)

INTERESTS

- •
- •

REFERENCES

Technology + Creativity + Design... Will's work represents the sum of these skills, but the result is much more than the sum of each part... I highly recommend Will.

Pedro Menezes, Senior Creative Director at Quaderno

Will has a broad and global experience for management. Having him as a classmate during our MBA was a fantastic experience. His neat vision and quick wit added great value for all of us! I highly recommend him as a professional.

— Fabio Machado, Owner at Global Link Consulting

Will Wright is an exceptionally talented young professional. Besides very well trained, he is deeply perceptive, responsible and supportive. His design recommendations I follow much to my delight. He should fully flourish in any business environment where an artistic bent is cherished.

— Alfredo Behrens, Professor, Cross-Cultural Management at FIA Business School, International MBA

Will brings together two very interesting traits based on his multicultural upbringing. His keen and trendy creativity shows his Brazilian DNA with a much-focused mindset on objectives. On his heritage, his British organisation counterparts in a very positive manner usually unseen in his line of work. By aggregating these traits makes him a differentiated professional that focuses in the established objectives.

— Arthur Wong, Marketing Manager, PR and Club Management at Ducati Motor Holding